The Community Experimental Repertory Theatre (C.E.R.T) Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Community Experimental Repertory Theatre (C.E.R.T) Collection
1976 - 1989
NPkMC-222-114
1.5 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
The Community Experimental Repertory Theatre
This collection contains documents, photographs, slides, negatives, newspaper clippings and performance programs covering the history and productions of the Community Experimental Repertory Theatre (C.E.R.T.) collected by the members and C.E.R.T. executive board.
Collection Overview
The Community Experimental Repertory Theatre (C.E.R.T.) Collection contains photographs, slides, negatives, documents, newspaper clippings, performance programs and advertisements relating to the performances and history of C.E.R.T. spanning from 1976 to 1989.
Acquisitions Information
This collection was donated to Marist College by the Community Experimental Repertory Theatre (C.E.R.T.).
Historical Note
The Community Experimental Repertory Theatre was created in 1970. Marist Professor Gerard A. Cox served as the founding chairman of the board of directors for ten years. In 1976 The Marist Theatre Guild, the Community Experimental Repertory Theatre, and the Children’s Theatre united to form the Marist College Council on Theatre Arts.
James Britt (re: Jim Britt Memorial Award plaque) who was the Director of the Theatre Guild in 1961, created The Student Director Program "to foster a finer understanding of the Dramatic Arts."
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Arrangement of the Collection
These records are organized into four series: 1) Documents, 2) Slides, photographs, and photo negatives, 3) Scrapbooks, and 4) Miscellany
Materials are arranged by subject.
- 1. Documents, 1975 - 1983; 1; Box: 1 Folders: 1 - 16
  Series contains the C.E.R.T. constitution, minutes from Board meetings, financial reports and other documents relating to the Community Experimental Repertory Theatre.
  By subject
  - C.E.R.T. constitution and by-laws (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Awards (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - Involvement Drama (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - C.E.R.T. members (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - Newspaper articles (Folder 5, Box 1)
  - C.E.R.T. Board minutes and Financial Reports: 1975 (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - C.E.R.T. Board minutes and Financial Reports: 1976 (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - C.E.R.T. Board minutes and Financial Reports: 1977 (Folder 8, Box 1)
  - C.E.R.T. Board minutes and Financial Reports: 1978 (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - C.E.R.T. Board minutes and Financial Reports: 1979 (Folder 10, Box 1)
  - C.E.R.T. Board minutes and Financial Reports: 1980 (Folder 11, Box 1)
  - C.E.R.T. Board minutes and Financial Reports: 1981 (Folder 12, Box 1)
  - C.E.R.T. Board minutes and Financial Reports: 1982 (Folder 13, Box 1)
  - C.E.R.T. Board minutes and Financial Reports: 1983 (Folder 14, Box 1)
  - C.E.R.T. Papers (Folder 15, Box 1)
  - C.E.R.T. Ads (Folder 16, Box 1)
- 2. Slides, Photographs, and Photo Negatives, 2; Box: 1 Folders: 17 - 58
  Series contains Slides, Photographs and Photo Negatives of C.E.R.T. productions and events.
  Alphabetical
  - “12N” Slides (Folder 17, Box 1)
  - Amelia Bedelia slides, photographs and negatives (Folder 18, Box 1)
  - Androcles and the Lion slides and photographs (Folder 19, Box 1)
  - April, 1989 slides (Folder 20, Box 1)
  - Arkansaw Bear slides and photographs (Folder 21, Box 1)
  - A Case for Two Spies photographs and negatives (Folder 22, Box 1)
  - C.E.R.T. School of Performing Arts slides (Folder 23, Box 1)
  - Charlotte’s Web slides (Folder 24, Box 1)
  - A Christmas Carol negatives (Folder 25, Box 1)
  - Circus in the Wind photographs (Folder 26, Box 1)
  - Dance slides (Folder 27, Box 1)
  - Diary of Anne Frank slides (Folder 28, Box 1)
  - Duck slides (Folder 29, Box 1)
  - Fame photographs (Folder 30, Box 1)
  - Fish slides (Folder 31, Box 1)
  - Glass Menagerie slides (Folder 32, Box 1)
  - The Great Zingu photographs (Folder 33, Box 1)
  - Harvey Eastman Remembered photographs (Folder 34, Box 1)
  - Heidi 3/21/86 slides (Folder 35, Box 1)
  - Indian slides (Folder 36, Box 1)
  - The Invention photographs and negatives (Folder 37, Box 1)
  - June, 1989 slides (Folder 38, Box 1)
  - Lion I slides (Folder 39, Box 1)
  - The Lion, the Witch and the Wardrobe photographs (Folder 40, Box 1)
  - Marmalade Gumdrops photographs (Folder 41, Box 1)
  - OK Theatre photographs and negatives (Folder 42, Box 1)
  - Poughkeepsie Tri-centennial photographs (Folder 43, Box 1)
  - Professor How? Vanderbilt slides (Folder 44, Box 1)
  - Puppeteer slides (Folder 45, Box 1)
  - Rags to Riches photographs (Folder 46, Box 1)
  - Ransom of Red Chief slides (Folder 47, Box 1)
  - The Red Shoes photographs (Folder 48, Box 1)
  - The Reluctant Dragon photographs and negatives (Folder 49, Box 1)
  - Rip Van Winkle photographs (Folder 50, Box 1)
  - Tour slides (Folder 51, Box 1)
  - Treasure Island slides (Folder 52, Box 1)
  - Slide positive photographs (Folder 53, Box 1)
  - 8x10 production photographs (1 of 2) (Folder 54, Box 1)
  - 8x10 production photographs (2 of 2) (Folder 55, Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous slides (Folder 56, Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Folder 57, Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous negatives (Folder 58, Box 1)
- 3. Scrapbooks, 1976 - 1986; 3; Box: 1 Folders: 59 - 65
  Series contains The Scrapbooks contain pictures, newspaper clippings, theatre programs and correspondence made by C.E.R.T. members.
  Chronological
  - 1976 (Folder 59, Box 1)
  - 1976-1980 (1 of 2) (Folder 60, Box 1)
  - 1976-1980 (2 of 2) (Folder 61, Box 1)
  - 1980-1983 (1 of 3) (Folder 62, Box 1)
  - 1980-1983 (2 of 3) (Folder 63, Box 1)
  - 1980-1983 (3 of 3) (Folder 64, Box 1)
  - 1986 page (Folder 65, Box 1)
- 4.Miscellany, 1983; 4; Box: 1 66
  Series contains miscellaneous items related to C.E.R.T.
  - 1983 Jim Britt Memorial Award plaque (Folder 66, Box 1)